Please have a seat.
请坐。
Sir.
先生。
Okay.
好的。
Sir,
先生，
what can I do for you?
我能为你做什么？
Please give this to Ms. Lin and tell her that I am here for her.
请把这个交给林女士 ，并告诉她我是为她而来。
=Ripe Town= =Episode 9=
=成熟小镇= =第9集=
The beard is different.
胡子不一样。
It can't be painted like how you do your eyebrows.
不能 像画眉毛那样画。
I actually don't know how to do my eyebrows well.
其实我也不知道 怎么修眉毛。
You really look like your father.
你真的很像你的父亲。
I saw your brother on the street.
我在街上看到你哥哥了。
He looks more like your mother.
他看起来更像你的母亲。
You are more like your father.
你更像你的父亲。
I knew you had an affair with my father.
我知道你和我父亲有染。
My mother knew it too.
我妈妈也知道。
Do you resent me?
你怨恨我吗？
Maybe when I was a child.
也许当我还是个孩子的时候。
But now if you ask me,
但现在如果你问我，
I can't say what you did wrong.
我不能说你做错了什么。
I don't know many things about my father,
关于我父亲的很多事我都不太了解
but I think you should know.
但我想你应该知道。
I wanted to ask you a long time ago.
我很久以前就想问你了。
What do you want to ask?
你想问什么？
I will tell you what I know.
我会告诉你我所知道的。
Did my father only come to see you every time he came here?
我父亲每次来都是为了来看你吗？
Yes.
是的。
He only visited me every time.
他每次都只来看我一次。
He had never looked for anyone else.
他从来没有寻找过其他人。
Don't men love juggling different women?
男人不是都喜欢玩弄不同的女人吗？
Your father didn't.
你父亲没有。
Are you here to ask me about your father?
你来这里是 为了向我打听你父亲的事吗？
Not really.
并不真地。
But tell me about him first.
但先告诉我关于他的事。
My parents died during a plague.
我的父母在一场瘟疫中去世了。
I was sold to Cuihua Tower by my uncle when I was 11.
我十一岁时被叔叔卖到了翠华楼。
I started learning painting and calligraphy,
我开始学习绘画 和书法，
playing music, and singing songs
演奏音乐和唱歌
till 14.
直到 14 点。
My menstruation came late, giving me another year of an easy life.
我的月经来得晚了， 让我又过了一年安逸的生活。
But when I was 15,
但当我15岁的时候，
the day finally came.
这一天终于来了。
I had to entertain guests.
我必须招待客人。
I found an opportunity
我找到了一个机会
to escape.
逃离。
You ran from Cuihua Tower?
你是从翠华楼跑出来的？
Where did you run?
你跑到哪里去了？
I had nowhere to go.
我无处可去。
I didn't know the way.
我不认识路。
I didn't have any money.
我没有钱。
But weren't you afraid of running into bad guys?
但你就不怕 遇到坏人吗？
Before thinking of that,
在想到这一点之前，
I encountered one.
我就遇到过一个。
Girl, stop. I'm not a bad guy.
姑娘，停下来。我不是坏人。
I told you to stop.
我告诉过你停下来。
Let me take good care of you.
让我好好照顾你。
Let go!
松手！
Get lost.
迷路。
Don't be afraid. I'm an official.
别害怕。我是一名官员。
Where do you live? I can take you home.
你住在哪里？ 我可以带你回家。
Stop following me.
不要跟着我。
I am a bailiff from the Yamen.
我是衙门的法警。
Tell me where your home is.
告诉我你家在哪里。
I will take you home.
我会带你回家。
Mind your own business.
管好自己的事吧。
I didn't break the law.
我没有违法。
You're a young girl,
你是一个年轻的女孩，
walking alone in the middle of the night,
半夜独自行走，
and you can't tell where to go.
你不知道该去哪里。
Honestly,
诚实地，
I can take you to the Yamen.
我可以带你去衙门。
If you don't tell me,
如果你不告诉我
I will do that.
我去做。
I have nowhere to go.
我无处可去。
What?
什么？
How can you have nowhere to go?
你怎么能无处可去呢？
I ran away from a place.
我逃离了一个地方。
What?
什么？
From where?
从哪里？
Are you
你是
a maid from a wealthy family,
一个富裕家庭的女仆，
or a girl from a brothel?
还是妓院的女孩？
Cuihua Tower.
Cuihua Tower.
If you want to go back there,
如果你想回到那里
I can take you back.
我可以带你回去。
Please don't take me back.
请不要带我回去。
If they know I escaped,
如果他们知道我逃跑了
they will kill me.
他们会杀了我。
I can help you.
我可以帮你。
I will make up a story to cover for you.
我会编一个故事来掩饰你。
When you were kidnapped by a villain,
当你被坏人绑架时
I happened to see you.
我碰巧见到你了。
I drove away the villain and saved you.
我赶走了恶棍，救了你。
I'm a bailiff, and they will believe me.
我是一名法警，他们会相信我的。
Don't take me back.
别送我回去。
Please don't.
请不要。
If you really don't want to go back...
如果你实在不想回去的话...
Are you hungry?
你饿了吗？
I'll go buy you some food.
我去给你买点吃的。
Wait here for me.
在这里等我。
I just gave you all my money.
我刚刚把我所有的钱都给了你。
Hold this lantern.
拿着这个灯笼。
Here.
这里。
I also bought you rice milk.
我还给你买了米浆。
Are you full?
你吃饱了吗？
If I finish this bun,
如果我吃完这个面包
you will take me back to Cuihua Tower?
你会带我回翠华楼吗？
If you want to go back,
如果你想回去的话
I will take you back.
我会带你回去的。
If you don't want to,
如果你不想的话
I will pretend I never saw you.
我会假装我从未见过你。
What if I can't make up my mind?
如果我拿不定主意怎么办？
I will wait for you to decide.
我会等你决定。
I am full.
我吃饱了。
Take me back to Cuihua Tower.
带我回翠华楼。
What happened after that?
之后发生了什么？
I came back and started to entertain clients.
我回来后 开始招待客户。
I became popular very soon.
我很快就受欢迎了。
Well,
出色地，
half a year later,
半年后，
your father came.
你父亲来了。
This is not even enough to pay Siniang for a chat.
这连四娘聊天的钱都不够。
Sir.
先生。
Why don't you switch to someone else?
你为什么不换成别人呢？
I don't want anyone else.
我不想要其他人。
How much does it cost
它要多少钱
to chat with her?
和她聊天？
20 taels of silver.
银子20两。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
Ms. Zhao, don't you remember him?
赵小姐，你不记得他了吗？
He is...
他是...
He is the bailiff who saved me.
他是救了我的法警。
He didn't wear an official uniform.
他没有穿官方制服。
I didn't recognize him.
我没认出他来。
Let me spend some time with him.
让我和他一起度过一些时间。
I'll talk with him.
我会和他谈谈。
It can be a way to repay his kindness.
这也算是报答他的恩情的一种方式吧。
I know you love money so much.
我知道你非常爱钱。
But if other officials know
但如果其他官员知道
you are so ungrateful and send away
你真是忘恩负义，还送走了
the savior of my life,
我生命的救星，
none of them will be willing to help you
他们都不愿意帮助你
when you need them.
当你需要它们时。
Sir.
先生。
I'm sorry I didn't recognize you.
很抱歉我没认出你。
You will forgive me, right?
你会原谅我的，对吗？
It's alright.
没关系。
Even though I'm a businesswoman,
尽管我是一名商人，
I'm grateful.
我很感激。
Are you?
你是？
Of course.
当然。
That's important to us.
这对我们很重要。
The scholar, Mr. Wang
学者王先生
is a regular here.
是这里的常客。
He once said
他曾经说过
there must be women
必须有女人
of sentiment in a pleasure house.
游乐屋里的情感。
The tea is already cold.
茶已经冷了。
I'll have someone get you some hot tea.
我会让人给你倒杯热茶。
No, thanks.
不，谢谢。
I'm leaving now.
现在我要走了。
Now?
现在？
Why did you come here?
你为什么来这里？
Just to see you.
只想见你。
To see me?
来看我？
It costs money to see me.
见我要花钱。
Don't spend your money on me anymore.
别再为我花你的钱了。
I'm not worth it.
我不值得。
I've saved for eight months,
我存了八个月的钱
getting around six taels of silver.
得银子六两左右。
To have tea with you,
和你一起喝茶，
it costs 20 taels.
花费20两。
In this case,
在这种情况下，
I can see you once
我可以见到你一次
every two years.
每两年一次。
What's the point?
重点是什么？
It doesn't matter.
没关系。
However,
然而，
the thought
那个想法
of never seeing you again
再也见不到你
is killing me.
快要死了。
Yanzhi Alley.
Yanzhi Alley.
The back door of Cuihua Tower is on Yanzhi Alley.
翠华楼的后门 在烟枝巷。
Wait for me there three days later
三天后在那里等我
at six in the evening.
晚上六点。
I'll go to see you.
我会去看你。
So you were in a relationship before my father married my mother.
所以在我父亲和我母亲结婚之前你们就已经恋爱了 。
You are from Cuihua Tower,
你来自翠华楼，
so you two cannot be together.
所以你们两个不可能在一起。
Actually, your father once redeemed me.
事实上，你的父亲曾经救赎过我。
To redeem me,
为了救赎我，
your father did a lot of things
你父亲做了很多事
he shouldn't have done.
他不应该这样做。
After he really redeemed me,
当他真正救赎了我之后，
I realized
我意识到
my body could never be redeemed
我的身体永远无法救赎
ever since he brought me back
自从他把我带回来
to Cuihua Tower.
到翠华楼。
Why?
为什么？
I'm 38 this year.
我今年38岁了。
One in ten prostitutes
十分之一的妓女
can live
可以生活
this long.
这么长。
Really?
真的吗？
Most of us could be killed
我们大多数人都可能被杀
by being pregnant.
通过怀孕。
They won't let us give birth once we are pregnant.
一旦我们怀孕了，他们就不会让我们生孩子。
The abortion method is deadly.
堕胎方法是致命的。
It involves medicines
涉及到药物
like cinnabar, cantharides,
如朱砂、斑蝥、
and a little dose of arsenic.
和少量的砷。
It could kill two lives together.
它可能会杀死两个人的生命。
And some survived and gave birth.
有些人幸存下来并生下孩子。
But life for them is bitter.
但生活对他们来说是苦涩的。
Their kids are called turtles.
他们的孩子被称为乌龟。
Ms. Lin.
林女士。
Have you ever
你有没有
been pregnant before?
以前怀孕过吗？
I've never been pregnant.
我从未怀孕过。
If I can't bear children,
如果我不能生育孩子
how can I marry your father?
我怎样才能嫁给你父亲？
Fortunately, your father married your mother.
幸运的是，你的父亲 娶了你的母亲。
Look.
看。
He's lucky.
他是幸运的。
He has a daughter so much like him.
他有一个女儿，非常像他。
How did you know the money was from me?
你怎么知道钱是我给的？
Your money is scented.
你的钱有香味。
You didn't come to return it to me, did you?
你不是来 还给我的，是吗？
I wanted to ask about my dad and Mr. Xue.
我想问 一下我爸爸和薛先生的情况。
Or should I ask about my dad and Lu Zhi?
还是该问问我爸和路植的事？
Sui Laosan.
Sui Laosan.
Coming.
未来。
Ms. Lin, what can I do for you?
林小姐，有什么可以帮您的吗？
Bring the new brocade to...
把新锦缎带到...
To this gentleman.
致这位先生。
The one with azure color, densely woven with gold and silver thread.
其颜色蔚蓝， 以金银线密织而成。
Got it.
知道了。
Leave the door open.
让门开着。
I want to get some air.
我想呼吸点空气。
Alright.
好吧。
Bring Sangeng over.
Bring Sangeng over.
I'll tell him everything I know.
我会把我知道的一切都告诉他。
Gui's.
贵的.
You must not get involved.
你一定不要参与其中。
You must not have any connection
您一定没有任何联系
with Mr. Xue.
和薛先生。
This must be it.
一定是这个。
It's the only new tomb here.
这是这里唯一的新坟墓。
Ms. Lin.
林女士。
When you meet my father down there,
当你在那里遇见我父亲时
have a good life with him.
和他一起过美好的生活。
Don't part ways again.
别再分开了
Gui's.
贵的.
It's okay.
没关系。
She's suffered too much.
她受的苦太多了。
I wanted to get a tombstone for her.
我想为她立一块墓碑。
But on the tombstone,
但在墓碑上，
there's a title in front of the name,
名字前面有一个标题，
like mother, sister, or wife.
例如母亲、姐妹或妻子。
But...
但...
I don't know what to inscribe for her.
我不知道该为她写什么。
My mother suffered as well,
我妈也受过苦，
but not as much as she did.
但没有她做的那么多。
My mother has me and my brother,
我妈妈有我和我弟弟，
but she only has a lonely tomb
但她只有一座孤独的坟墓
without even a stone.
连一块石头都没有。
Did the killer leave a note for Ms. Lin as well?
凶手是否也给林女士留下了字条？
In his youth his vital force is unstable.
在他年轻的时候， 他的生命力不稳定。
He should guard against lust.
他应该戒除淫欲。
It is easy.
这很容易。
Even I could understand it.
就连我也能理解。
What did you say?
你说什么？
What do you think that phrase means?
你认为这句话的意思是什么？
Youths are prone to impulsiveness.
青少年容易冲动。
So be careful of lust for women.
所以要小心对女人的情欲。
No.
不。
I'm not right?
我说的不对吧？
Yes,
是的，
you are right.
你是对的。
The problem lies elsewhere.
问题出在别处。
(Worship the wrong ghost.)
（崇拜错误的鬼魂。）
The victim is Zhao Youren, an Imperial Scholar.
受害者是 翰林学士赵友仁。
He originally came from a respected family.
他原本来自 一个受人尊敬的家庭。
But his family collapsed.
但他的家庭却崩溃了。
He liked to raise pigeons.
他喜欢养鸽子。
He had his throat cut.
他的喉咙被割断了。
Again?
再次？
The message was written in rouge. It reads, "Worship the wrong ghost."
这封信是用胭脂写的。 上面写着：“崇拜错误的鬼魂。”
You worshiped
你崇拜
the wrong ghost.
错误的鬼魂。
I think this killer is using the body to send us messages.
我认为这个杀手正在利用身体 向我们发送信息。
The message left for Lin Siniang is too blunt.
给林四娘留下的信息 太生硬了。
But the previous ones
但之前的那些
(He should guard against lust.) carry a hidden meaning.
（应戒淫欲。） 带有隐含意义。
And this victim has the same cause
而这位受害者也有同样的原因
and state of death as Lin Siniang.
以及林四娘的死亡状态。
He was deliberately dressed up as a woman.
他故意打扮 成女人。
And the message. "Worship the wrong ghost."
还有消息。 “拜错鬼了。”
You worshiped the wrong ghost.
你崇拜了错误的鬼魂。
- You mean... - The killer wants to tell us
- 你的意思是... - 凶手想告诉我们
that he didn't kill Lin Siniang.
林四娘不是他杀的。
(1589 AD) (Lu Yuanbao's condition was not stable.)
（公元1589年） （陆元宝病情不稳定。）
(It never got better.)
（情况从未变得更好。）
(He began to have nightmares,)
（他开始做噩梦，）
(dreaming about the deceased.)
（梦见死者。）
Guards!
卫兵！
Lu Zhong.
Lu Zhong.
I dreamt of Tao Laowu.
我梦见了陶老五。
(I remember him.)
（我记得他。）
Go kill him.
去杀了他吧。
Kill him.
杀了他。
(He was killed 13 years ago.)
（他13年前被杀了。）
It's good.
很好。
Well,
出色地，
was he really killed?
他真的被杀了吗？
Go back to sleep.
回去睡觉。
(You stay here.)
（你留在这里。）
(Watch him. I'm leaving.)
（看着他。我要走了。）
Tian Shun Xiang.
Tian Shun Xiang.
Accounts settled.
账目结清了。
Mr. Li, thank you.
李先生，谢谢您。
Not at all, Master Lu.
卢老师，一点也不。
Fuxing Shop.
复兴店.
Master Lu, are you done?
卢老师，你说完了吗？
Almost.
几乎。
When you're done, go and visit Mr. Lu.
忙完了就去拜访陆先生吧。
In the back garden.
后花园里。
Isn't he in the study?
他不是在书房吗？
Mr. Lu is in good spirits today and wants to have a drink.
陆先生今天心情很好 ，想喝一杯。
mr. Sun.
先生。太阳。
You've worked hard these days.
这些天你辛苦了。
I'm doing my job.
我正在做我的工作。
Mr. Lu, this is the account book from last month.
卢先生，这是上个月的账本。
No rush.
不着急。
Sit, and have a drink with me.
坐下来和我喝一杯吧。
Mr. Lu, Dr. Cheng does not permit you to drink alcohol.
陆先生，程医生不许您 喝酒。
The doctor only wishes everyone to take medicine.
医生只希望大家 吃药。
Just ignore him.
不理他就好了。
Bottoms up.
一饮而尽。
This is the old grain wine,
这是老粮酒，
just shipped over via the Yangtze River.
刚刚从长江运过来。
How's the taste?
味道怎么样？
Your wine is naturally good.
你的酒自然是好酒。
Sweet boy.
可爱的男孩。
Lu Zhi.
Lu Zhi.
How much can you drink?
你能喝多少？
I can't drink much.
我不能喝太多。
Just drink as much as you like.
你想喝多少就喝多少。
I will test your drinking capacity.
我来测试一下你的饮酒能力。
If you say so,
如果你这么说的话
I will
我会
get drunk here.
在这里喝醉。
Drinking like this is boring.
这样喝酒很无聊。
We need to play a drinking game.
我们需要玩一个喝酒的游戏。
Let me guess the account you just settled today.
让我猜猜你今天刚结的帐 。
Can you do it?
你可以做到吗？
Within five taels of difference,
五两之差以内，
I win.
我赢了。
And you will drink.
你会喝酒。
If I guess wrong, I'll drink.
如果我猜错了，我就喝酒。
mr. Sun.
先生。太阳。
Is this your excuse to drink more?
这是你多喝点酒的借口吗？
Do you dare?
你敢吗？
Why not?
为什么不？
You're as outright as me.
你和我一样直率。
Someone, bring a larger bowl.
来人，拿一个大点的碗来。
Let's start.
开始吧。
Alright.
好吧。
Hey Shop.
嘿商店。
Two thousand...
两千...
2,950 taels in total.
一共2950两。
How is it?
如何？
Guessed right.
猜对了。
Drink up.
喝完。
Alright.
好吧。
Again.
再次。
Long Chang Sheng.
Long Chang Sheng.
5,292 taels.
5,292 taels.
You guessed right.
你猜对了。
I'm lucky.
我很幸运。
Drink.
喝。
Again.
再次。
Well...
出色地...
Wait a moment.
稍等。
I will choose one shop.
我会选择一家店。
And you make a guess.
你猜一下。
Alright, as you say.
好吧，正如你所说。
This is too easy for you.
这对你来说太容易了。
No.
不。
This one...
这个...
This...
这...
Lu Zhi.
Lu Zhi.
I can tell
我可以告诉
you're playing for time.
你是在争取时间。
How did you know that?
你怎么知道的？
Lion Restaurant.
狮子餐厅。
Lion Restaurant?
狮子餐厅？
You got me.
你抓住了我。
744 taels.
744 taels.
You guessed it right.
你猜对了。
Drink.
喝。
Okay.
好的。
You keep drinking.
你继续喝酒。
It's too boring.
太无聊了。
I'll join you for a drink.
我会和你一起喝一杯。
How on earth did you guess it?
你到底是怎么猜到的？
I can guess.
我能猜到。
You can guess.
你可以猜猜。
Lu Zhi.
Lu Zhi.
Are you drunk?
你醉了吗？
mr. Sun.
先生。太阳。
Did you
你是否
settle the accounts with the bookkeepers in advance?
提前和簿记员算账吗？
No.
不。
You haven't been out for over a month.
你已经一个多月没有出门了。
And those bookkeepers have never come.
而那些簿记员从来没有来过。
How did you know?
你怎么知道？
Lu Zhi.
Lu Zhi.
Remember one thing.
记住一件事。
There is nothing, big or small,
没有什么，无论大小，
in my house that I don't know.
在我家，我不知道。
Mr. Lu, I got it.
陆先生，我明白了。
After they settled accounts
他们算完账后
with me,
与我一起，
they went
他们去了
to tell you one by one.
一一告诉你。
You put these accounts in your sleeve.
你把这些账户放在你的袖子里。
I saw it just now. When you were walking,
我刚才看到了。 当你走路的时候，
you turned your head and looked inside.
你转过头看向里面。
I saw it.
我看到了。
You're cheating.
你在作弊。
You have to drink.
你必须喝酒。
Lu Zhi.
Lu Zhi.
You are really drunk.
你真的醉了。
I'm not drunk.
我没醉。
I haven't finished my drink yet.
我还没喝完呢
But why did you make a fool of me?
但你为什么要愚弄我呢？
Are you trying to get me drunk?
你是想把我灌醉吗？
No.
不。
Even if you didn't do this,
即使你没有这样做，
I would still drink a lot.
我还是会喝很多。
I understand.
我明白。
I see.
我懂了。
Mr. Lu, you are trying to seem mysterious
陆先生，你想 显得神秘
and well-informed.
并且消息灵通。
You know everything.
你什么都知道。
You are trying to warn me.
你正试图警告我。
So, you don't trust me.
所以，你不信任我。
You are trying to scare me.
你想吓唬我。
So I dare not mess around.
所以我不敢乱来。
Don't you know me?
你不认识我吗？
You don't have to do this.
你不必这样做。
Well,
出色地，
I have always respected you as my father.
我一直尊您 为我的父亲。
What did you say?
你说什么？
mr. Sun.
先生。太阳。
Without you,
没有你，
I, a beggar,
我，一个乞丐，
would have died on the streets long ago.
早就死在街上了。
Although you don't have a son.
虽然你没有儿子。
I can be your son.
我可以成为你的儿子。
I will certainly respect you more than anyone.
我当然会 比任何人都更尊重你。
I will take care of you during your later life.
你以后的生活我会照顾你的。
I will mourn for you.
我会为你哀悼。
mr. Sun.
先生。太阳。
I have always wanted to call you father.
我一直想叫你爸爸。
Lu Zhi.
Lu Zhi.
They all call you Master Lu.
他们都叫你鲁大师。
Why?
为什么？
They keep calling me that.
他们一直这么叫我。
They have seen how well you treat me.
他们已经看到你对我有多好。
I tried to stop them.
我试图阻止他们。
I told them to stop calling me that,
我告诉他们别再这么叫我了
but they didn't listen to me...
但他们不听我的...
You lowly beast.
你这个卑贱的野兽。
Do you want a father?
你想要一个父亲吗？
I'll give you one.
我给你一个。
You know this lowly servant on his knees.
你认识这个 跪着的卑微仆人。
My attendant, Lu Zhi.
My attendant, Lu Zhi.
Somehow,
不知何故，
he was possessed,
他着魔了，
telling everyone
告诉大家
that I wanted to take him as my adopted son.
我想收他 为我的养子。
He even let everyone call him Master Lu.
还让大家叫他鲁大师。
What are you?
你是做什么的？
A lowly servant.
一个卑微的仆人。
How dare you.
你怎么敢。
I just kept you as a dog,
我只是把你当狗养
but you took yourself for a man.
但你却把自己当成一个男人了。
He said he would take care of me in my old age.
他说他会照顾我 晚年。
I know your trick.
我知道你的伎俩。
You think that since I have no children,
你以为我没有孩子，
all my property will belong to you.
我所有的财产都属于你。
You want a father, right?
你想要一个父亲，对吗？
All the men of the Lu family are here.
陆家的男人都来了。
Later, kowtow
随后，磕头
and ask each man
并询问每个人
who wants to be your father.
谁想成为你的父亲。
If his surname is Zhang,
如果他姓张的话
your name will be Zhang Zhi.
你的名字叫张志。
If his surname is Li,
如果他姓李的话
your name will be Li Zhi.
你的名字叫李智。
Do it now.
现在做。
Help him.
帮助他。
Speak.
说话。
Slap him.
打他一巴掌。
Go on.
继续。
Hit him until he speaks.
打他直到他说话。
mr. Sun.
先生。太阳。
I'll speak for him.
我会为他说话。
What a surprise.
真是一个惊喜。
I can't believe you'll help him with it.
我不敢相信你会帮助他。
Chen Wang, you are quite righteous.
陈旺，你很有正义感。
But I admire righteous people.
但我敬佩正直的人。
Then you two find a father together.
然后你们两个一起找到一个父亲。
Okay.
好的。
Well...
出色地...
Kowtow.
磕头。
Okay.
好的。
Miao, are you willing...
淼，你愿意吗……
Louder.
大声点。
Miao, are you willing to be a father
淼，你愿意当爸爸吗？
to me and Lu Zhi?
to me and Lu Zhi?
Miao, did you hear?
淼，你听到了吗？
Yes, I did.
是的，我做到了。
So what do you say?
你认为呢？
I...
我...
I am unwilling.
我不愿意。
Miao, you lost your chance.
淼，你失去了机会。
Step aside.
退到一边去。
Are you willing to be our father?
你愿意当我们的父亲吗？
No.
不。
Chen Wang.
Chen Wang.
I'll do it myself.
我自己来做。
Are you willing to be my father?
你愿意当我的父亲吗？
No.
不。
(In the end, Lu Zhi didn't get a father.)
（最终， 卢植没有得到父亲。）
(Later, )
（之后， ）
(Lu Yuanbao sent him to a rural area)
（陆元宝送他下乡）
(to do farm work.)
（干农活。）
Lu Zhi.
Lu Zhi.
Where are the others?
其他人在哪里？
(You asked them to wait outside.)
（你让他们在外面等。）
I was absorbed in writing and forgot.
我全神贯注地写着，却忘记了。
(I heard you.)
（我听到了。）
(You didn't call them.)
（你没有给他们打电话。）
Lu Zhong.
Lu Zhong.
According to the rules,
根据规则，
we should...
我们应该...
(Kill him.)
（杀了他。）
(I'll do it.)
（我会做的。）
I've thought about it these days.
这些天我一直在思考这个问题。
Well,
出色地，
I overreacted.
我反应过度了。
After that day,
那天之后，
this kid must have hated me.
这小子一定很讨厌我吧。
I can't use him anymore.
我不能再使用他了。
It's quite a pity.
实在是太可惜了。
(Keeping him is dangerous.)
（留住他是危险的。）
(I'm afraid...)
（我耽心...）
You're afraid of him?
你怕他吗？
He's just a servant.
他只是一个仆人。
He can't be compared to the others.
他无法与其他人相比。
Those were ruthless bandits.
那些都是无情的强盗。
He's just an attendant.
他只是一个服务员。
I just pampered him too much.
我只是太宠他了。
So he dared to be presumptuous in front of me.
所以他才敢 在我面前放肆。
I have to make him afraid.
我必须让他害怕。
When I call him,
当我打电话给他时，
he will shiver.
他会发抖。
When I glare,
当我怒目而视时，
he will wet his pants.
他会弄湿他的裤子。
It's fun.
好有趣。
Call him back in a few days.
几天后给他回电话。
He can't be my attendant.
他不可能成为我的侍从。
Let him do some kind of rough work.
让他做一些粗活。
If he makes any movements,
如果他有任何动作
don't hesitate.
不要犹豫。
Mr. Zhong.
Mr. Zhong.
(Let's find a private place.)
（我们找个私人地方吧。）
Mr. Zhong, have you gone fishing?
钟先生，你去钓鱼了吗？
There's fat fish in the river.
河里有肥鱼。
Mr. Lu asked me to kill you.
陆先生要我杀了你。
(At that time, I told Lu Zhi)
（当时我告诉路植）
(that Mr. Lu asked me to kill him.)
（陆先生要我杀了他。）
(No Rank in Penalty)
（处罚不分等级）
???In the middle of the bone, and beside the blade???
???在骨头中间， 刀刃旁边???
???There's something sweet and sticky???
???有一些又甜又粘的东西???
???Biting through the old time???
???穿越旧时光???
???Some cry, and some sleep???
???有的哭，有的睡？？？
???Abundant offerings are served for sacrifice???
??? 祭祀的祭品很丰富???
???There are barren mounds, with flies flying around???
???荒丘荒， 苍蝇乱飞???
???Remote ancient road and prosperous city???
???偏远古道 、繁华都市???
???Wild fires never cease, withering and flourishing???
???野火永不停息， 枯萎又繁盛???
???A few columns of smoke are curling up???
???几柱烟雾袅袅升起???
???You make a wish???
???你许个愿吧???
???Empty promises and miserable stories???
???空洞的承诺和悲惨的故事???
???Disappear without trace???
？？？消失得无影无踪？？？
???Abundant offerings are served for sacrifice???
??? 祭祀的祭品很丰富???
???There are barren mounds, with flies flying around???
???荒丘荒， 苍蝇乱飞???
???Remote ancient road and prosperous city???
???偏远古道 、繁华都市???
???Wild fires never cease, withering and flourishing???
???野火永不停息， 枯萎又繁盛???